Guide to the Historical Planning publications collection, 1888-2002.
Historical Planning publications collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Historical Planning publications collection, 1888-2002.
15-3-3669
Cornell University.Fine Arts Library,
69.8 cubic feet.
Printed Materials, Publications, Reports
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Historical planning publications, transferred from the Fine Arts Library.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Historical planning publications, transferred from the Fine Arts Library, organized alphabetically by subject, outside of the subject "cities", the collection starts with the letter "H."
SUBJECTS
Names -
Cornell University.
Subjects -
Architecture--Study and teaching.; Building--Research--United States.; City planning.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Cities
Series II. Highways - Finance, Law, Surveys, Traffic
Series III. History
Series IV. Hospitals and Hospital Districts
Series V. Housing
Series VI. Industries
Series VII. Land - Use, Values
Series VIII. Law
Series IX. Local Government
Series X. Metropolitan Areas
Series XI. Mobile Homes and Parks
Series XII. Nations
Series XIII. Natural Resources
Series XIV. Neighborhoods
Series XV. New Towns
Series XVI. Organizations
Series XVII. Parking
Series XVIII. Parks
Series XIX. Population
Series XX. Preservation
Series XXI. Public Buildings
Series XXII. Public Finance
Series XXIII. Public Utilities
Series XXIV. Public Works
Series XXV. Rapid Transit
Series XXVI. Recreation
Series XXVII. Regional Planning
Series XXVIII. Sanitation
Series XXIX. Schools
Series XXX. Shopping Centers
Series XXXI. Social Planning
Series XXXII. States
Series XXXIII. Transportation
Series XXXIV. Urbanization
Series XXXV. Urban Renewal
Series XXXVI. Water
Series XXXVII. Zoning
Series XXXVIII. Other
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Cities
  - Cities - Foreign - Canada (Oversized), 1928-1958 (Box 69)
  - Cities - Foreign - England (Oversized), 1942 (Box 69)
  - Cities - Foreign - England - Canterbury (Oversized) (Box 69)
  - Cities - Foreign - England - Richmond (Oversized), 1945 (Box 69)
  - Cities - U.S. - Altoona, PA (Oversized) (Box 69)
  - Cities - U.S. - Chicago, IL (Oversized), 1964 (Box 62)
  - Cities - U.S. - El Paso, TX (Oversized), 1968 (Box 69)
  - Cities - U.S. - Grand Rapids, MI (Oversized), 1958 (Box 61)
  - Cities - U.S. - Ithaca, NY (1), 1953-1959 (Box 68, Folder 25)
  - Cities - U.S. - Ithaca, NY (2), 1968-1990 (Box 68, Folder 26)
  - Cities - U.S. - Ithaca, NY (3) (Box 68, Folder 27)
  - Cities - U.S. - Ithaca, NY (Oversized), 1969 (Box 69)
  - Cities - U.S. - Marlboro, NJ (Oversized), 1964 (Box 61)
  - Cities - U.S. - Orlando, FL (Oversized), 1950 (Box 61)
  - Cities - U.S. - Philadelphia, PA, 1960-1966 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Cities - U.S. - Philadelphia, PA, 1954 (Box 69)
  - Cities - U.S. - San Antonio, TX (Oversized), 1956 (Box 69)
  - Cities - U.S. - San Francisco, CA (Oversized), 1966 (Box 70)
  - Cities - U.S. - San Jose, CA (Oversized), 1969 (Box 62)
- Series II. Highways - Finance, Law, Surveys, Traffic
  - Highways- Finance- California- Connecticut (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - The California Freeway Program. Financing and Planning, June 20, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Local Road Costs in Connecticut, 1952-53 through 1956-57., January 1, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      Connecticut Public Expenditure Council
  - Highways- Finance- Mississippi- Ohio (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Highway Finance in Mississippi. A Survey of Sources and Uses of Highway, Road, and Street Funds in Mississippi., April 1, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      Governmental Affairs Committee, Mississippi Economic Council, State Chamber of Commerce
    - A General Study of Highway Taxation (Ohio), July 15, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      Ohio Department of Taxation
  - Highways- Finance- Tennessee (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Toll Roads for Tennessee. An Informational Report., May 1, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      Tennessee State Planning Commission
  - Highways-Law- General (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Model State Enabling Act Empowering State Highway Departments to Construct and Maintain Freeways and Parkways, July 1, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      U.S. Bureau of Public Roads
    - Better Laws for Better Highways, January 1, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Highway Research Board Bulletin 88, National Academy of Sciences- National Research Council
    - Highway Laws, January 1, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Highway Research Board Bulletin 145, National Academy of Sciences- National Research Council
    - Expressway Law. An Analysis., January 1, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Highway Research Board Special Report 26, National Academy of Sciences- National Research Council
    - Federal Legislation and Regulations Relating to Highway Construction, July 1, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Public Roads Administration, Federal Works Agency
    - First Progress Report, Committee on Highway Laws, November 11, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Department of Economics, Finance, and Administration, Highway Research Board
    - Federal -Aid Highway Act of 1959, January 1, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Status of Public Roads, 1959. Hearings Before a Subcommittee of the Committee on Public Works, U.S. Senate, 86th Congress., February 26, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - The First State Acts Authorizing Freeways, May 1, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Planning Broadcasts. A Bulletin of the American Planning and Civic Association
    - Compilation of State Laws Relating to "Freeways", January 1, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Legal Aspects of Controlling Highway Access, January 1, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Highways- Law- California- Connecticut (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - California. Chapter 359, Statutes 1939. An Act Authorizing Cities and Counties to Lay Out, Establish, Construct, and Acquire Freeways or Limited Access Streets and Highways and Providing Procedure for the Control Thereof., June 2, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Connecticut. Chapter 307, Public Acts of 1939, An Act Concerning Parkways, Freeways and Service Highways., June 19, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Connecticut. Chapter 307, Public Acts of 1939, An Act Concerning Parkways, Freeways and Service Highways. (With Amendments), March 4, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Highways- Law- Florida- Kansas (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Florida Highways Code. Highways, Bridges, and Ferries., January 1, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Motor Vehicle Laws of Kansas, January 1, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      State Highway Commission of Kansas
    - Highway Laws of Kansas, January 1, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Highways- Law- Maine- Maryland (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 283, Public Laws of 1939, An Act Concerning Certain Trunk Line Highways, April 21, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Maine
    - An Act to Add Five New Sections to article 89B of the Annotated Code of Maryland (1939 edition), title "State Roads," to be under new sub-title "Freeways," ... relating to the construction, designation, and regulation of freeways., January 1, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Maryland, 3 copies
  - Highways- Law- New York-North Dakota (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Resolution Authorizing the Issuance of $3,000,000 of Revenue Bonds, May 28, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Westchester Cross County Parkway Authority
    - Cahill's Consolidated Laws of New York, 1937 Supplement, Chapter 27., January 1, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      2 copies
    - Better Laws Are Basic to Better Highways. An Analysis of the State Highway Laws of North Dakota and Recommendations for Their Improvement, January 1, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Automotive Safety Foundation, North Dakota State Highway Dept.
  - Highways- Law- Oklahoma, Rhode Island, West Virginia (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Enrolled Senate Bill No. 199. An Act relating to Soil Conservation and Highways and Roads..., May 7, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      State of Oklahoma
    - Rhode Island Public Laws of 1937, Chapter 2537, An Act Relative to the Construction, Maintenance, and Improvement of Freeways, April 27, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      State of Rhode Island, 2 copies
    - West Virginia, Chapter 110, Acts of Regular Session, 1939, An Act to Amend Article 4, Chapter Seventeen of the Code of West Virginia, ...., March 4, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      State of West Virginia, 1.5 copies
  - Highways - Pennsylvania - Bethlehem (Oversized), 1958 (Box 70)
  - Highways- Surveys and Plans- General (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Design of the War Department Building Road Network, December 2, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Joseph Barnett, Public Roads Administration, Federal Works Agency
    - Design of Arterial Routes In Urban Areas, March 13, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Highways - Surveys and Plans - Louisiana - New Orleans (Oversized), 1946 (Box 70)
  - Highways- Surveys and Plans- Massachusetts (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - City of Cambridge Proposed Post-War Highway Program., January 1, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      City Planning Board, folded map.
    - Special Report of the Metropolitan District Commission Relative to the Construction of a Radial Highway From a Point Near the South Station to the Neponset Bridge in Boston and Quincy., December 2, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Massachusetts.
    - The Improvement of Boylston Street, December 28, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Town of Brookline, Massachusetts, 1 map inserted.
    - The $19,400,000 Street Program for Boston, April 28, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Boston Municipal Research Bureau
    - City of Pittsfield Main Highways. A Plan of Street Thoroughfares., December 1, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Planning Board, City of Pittsfield
    - Mayor's Conference on Traffic, Report of Committee on Projects, March 4, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      The City Planning Board, Boston, Massachusetts
  - Highways- Surveys and Plans- Michigan (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - City of Detroit Proposed System of Trafficways, December 1, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - A Comprehensive Plan of Motorways for Detroit, January 1, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Michigan State Highway Department
    - Grand Rapids' Official Thoroughfare Plan and Resume of Study (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Metropolitan Grand Rapids Planning Association
    - A Master Highway Plan at Detroit, December 3, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Chicago Regional Planning Commission
  - Highways- Surveys and Plans- Minnesota (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - A Report on a Survey of Traffic on Major Arterial Streets and Trunk Highways and Recommendations and Plans for the Improvements of Traffic Facilities, May 1, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Minneapolis City Planning Commission
    - Preliminary Street Plan and Transit Plan (Duluth, MN), February 20, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      City Planning Commission, Duluth, Minnesota
  - Highways- Surveys and Plans- Missouri- Mississippi (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Styled Highways for Tomorrow In the St. Louis Metropolitan Region, January 1, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      St. Louis Chamber of Commerce, Missouri
    - Mississippi Highway Facts, January 1, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      Division of Highway Planning, Mississippi
    - Statistics for Highway Planning On State Highways, County Roads, City Streets, Mississippi, January 1, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      Mississippi State Highway Department
    - 1961 Statistics for Highway Planning on State Highways, County Roads, City Streets, January 1, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Holly Springs, Mississippi Thoroughfare Plan, March 1, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Highways- Surveys and Plans- Missouri- Mississippi (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - A Report Based On Montana State-wide Highway Planning Survey Data, July 1, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Montana Highway Department
  - Highways- Surveys and Plans- New England (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - A Highway System for New England, September 1, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      New England Regional Planning Commission
    - New England South Shore Highway. Measurement and Analysis of the Factors Used In the Determination of the Route in Connecticut, Rhode Island, Massachusetts, October 1, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      Interstate Study Committee for a New England South Shore Highway
    - New England South Shore Highway. Its Location and Feasibility., October 2, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - New England South Shore Highway. Its Function and Importance., July 1, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Highways - Surveys and Plans - New Jersey (Oversized), 1958 (Box 69)
  - Highways- Surveys and Plans- New York - Ohio (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - The Least Social Cost Corridor For Richmond Parkway (New York City, N.Y.), May 6, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      Wallace McHarg Roberts and Todd,
    - Elmira Road-- Ithaca's Front Door, July 20, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      City Planning Board, Ithaca, New York.
    - Highways- Buffalo Area, February 28, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      Single Map, New York.
    - A Report of Rochester's Major Street System, January 1, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      City Planning Commission
  - Highways- Surveys and Plans- Ohio (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Stark County, Ohio, Major Highway Plan, January 1, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      Stark County Regional Planning Commission
    - Major Thoroughfare Plan (Lorain County, OH), January 23, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      Lorain County Regional Planning Commission, Thoroughfares
    - Major Thoroughfares Preliminary Report, May 21, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      Toledo-Lucas County Plan Commissions, Ohio
    - Report on Relationships Between State Highway Authorities and Local Communities in Ohio, January 1, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      OPC-AIP Committee on Highways
    - Status of Express Highway Program, January 1, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      Regional Association of Cleveland, Several news article stapled inside
    - Interstate Highway System. Toledo, OH., July 1, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Highways- Surveys and Plans- Oregon (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Traffic Density Tables for 1942., October 1, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      Oregon State Highway Department
  - Highways- Surveys and Plans- Pennsylvania (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Preliminary Major Thoroughfare Plan (York County, PA), January 1, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      York County Planning Commission
    - Pennsylvania Turnpike Commission 1958 Annual Report, May 31, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - A Preview Report On Highways, September 1, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Philadelphia City Planning Commission
    - An Analysis of Road Intersections In Whitpain Township, June 1, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Montgomery County Planning Commission
    - Report On the Revision and Extension of the Street System in South Philadelphia, January 1, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Permanent Committee on Comprehensive Plans, Department of Public Works, Philadelphia, PA.
  - Highways- Surveys and Plans- Rhode Island - South Dakota (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - The Effect of Expressway Construction on Surrounding Properties (Providence, R.I.), December 1, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      City Plan Commission of Providence, R.I.
    - South Dakota Highways. Special Report For a Proposed Highway Program in South Dakota, 1941- 1950., December 1, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      South Dakota State Highway Planning Commission, 2 loose maps.
  - Highways- Surveys and Plans- Vermont (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Vermont's 1948 Highway Needs, January 1, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      Vermont State Highway Department
    - Supplement to the Montpelier Urban Arterial Report, January 1, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Montpelier Urban Arterial Report, January 1, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Highways- Surveys and Plans- Virginia (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Plan and Report of Major Thoroughfares and Collector Streets. Arlington County, Virginia., September 1, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      Arlington County Planning Commission
    - Primary Roads Recommended for Transfer to Secondary System, January 1, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      Virginia Department of Highways
    - The Secondary System of Highways and Their Future Development. A Preliminary Report of the State-wide Highway Planning Survey, June 1, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      Virginia Department of Highways, U.S. Bureau of Public Roads
    - Major Highway Plan, Part I. (Norfolk, VA), January 1, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      Norfolk City Planning Commission
    - The Influence of Limited Access Highways on Land Value and Land Use. The Lexington, Virginia Bypass., April 1, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      Virginia Council of Highway Investigation and Research
  - Highways- Surveys and Plans- Washington - Wisconsin (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Recommended Access Control for Washington State Highways, June 1, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      Automotive Safety Foundation
    - No Title. Draft Report to Citizens of Milwaukee Regarding Street Widening. (Box 6, Folder 20)
      H. Schuchardt?, Board of Public Land Commissioning, Milwaukee, WI
    - An Integrated Street System for Oshkosh, Wisconsin, December 1, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      Oshkosh Planning Commission
    - Wisconsin Highways., January 1, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      Interim Committee on Highways
  - Highways- Surveys and Plans- Foreign- Argentina (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - La Avenida Nueve de Julio. Caracteristicas Y Ventajas Funcionales Y Economicas De Su Apertura En Todo El Ancho De La Manzana (Buenos Aires), January 1, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      Centro Argentino de Ingenieros
    - La Avenida 9 de Julio. Caracteristicas de la Gran Obra Edilicia En Vias De Realizacion, August 1, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      Carlos M. della Paolera, Director Tecnico del Plan de Urbanizacion, Buenos Aires.
  - Highways- Surveys and Plans- Foreign- Canada - Great Britain (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - First Report to the Municipal Council (Montreal, QC), December 1, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Montreal Board of Research on Traffic and Transportation Problems
    - Summary Report on Traffic, Transit, Parking. Metropolitan Winnipeg (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Wilbur Smith & Associates.
    - A Survey of British Roads, January 19, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Reprinted from the Manchester Guardian
    - Traffic In Trouble. BRF's Photo Album of Britain's Obsolete Highways., October 14, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      British Road Federation. Press Release.
    - New Roads for Lancashire, September 10, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      British Road Federation.
    - New Roads for Lancashire. Press Release., March 13, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Speakers' Notes. Road Development and Motor Taxation, January 1, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Speakers' Notes. Press Release., April 3, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Highways- Traffic- General (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Estimated Average Daily Traffic on Routes Selected for Study If Operated As Toll Roads, January 1, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      Single map from "Toll roads and Free Roads," U.S. House Doc 272, 1st session, 76' Congress
    - A Comparison Between the Average Daily Number of Passenger Cars on Principal Routes Serving Transcontinental Traffic and the Average Daily Number of Passenger Cars on Other Important Routes In 1937, January 1, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      Single map,
    - The Influence of Zoning on High Buildings and Street Traffic, ca. 1924 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      Ernest P. Goodrich, Traffic Consultant, Plan of New York and Its Environs
    - National Conference on Street and Highway Safety, March 5, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      Committee on Metropolitan Traffic Facilities
    - Second National Conference on Street and Highway Safety, March 23, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      U.S. Department of Commerce, Herbert Hoover
    - Use and Capacity of City Streets, January 1, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      Hawley S. Simpson, American Society of Civil Engineers, Paper 1880.
    - Creating Safer Communities, January 1, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      Massachusetts Safety Council
    - Measuring the Potential Traffic of A Proposed Vehicular Crossing, February 1, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      N. Cherniack, American Society of Civil Engineers
    - Causes of Failure in Handling Traffic, November 1, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      Lewis W. McIntyre, American Society of Civil Engineers
    - Remedies to Relieve Traffic Congestion, ca. 1938 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      Donal M. McNeil, American Society of Civil Engineers
    - Fitting Traffic Control to Wartime, ca. 1941 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      Office of Defense Transportation
    - A Policy on Criteria for Marking and Signing No-Passing Zones on Two and Three Lane Roads, January 1, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      American Association of State Highway Officials
    - An Analysis of Urban Travel By Survey Technique, January 1, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      American Transit Association
  - Highways- Traffic- General (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Traffic Volume Trends, April 30, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Traffic Volume Trends, January 31, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Traffic Speed Trends, January 31, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Traffic Volume Trends, February 28, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Traffic Volume Trends, March 31, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Traffic Volume Trends, April 30, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Traffic Volume Trends, May 31, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Traffic Volume Trends, June 30, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Traffic Volume Trends, July 31, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Traffic Volume Trends, August 31, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Traffic Volume Trends, September 30, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Traffic Volume Trends, October 31, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Traffic Volume Trends, November 29, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Traffic Volume Trends, December 31, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Highways- Traffic- General (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Circulation and Land Use (Box 3, Folder 27)
      Wayne D. Heydecker, Regional Plan Association Consultant,
    - 1) Traffic Regulations in Large Cities and Their Suburbs; Traffic Signals; Design and Layout of Roads and Adaptation to Traffic Requirements in Built Up Areas; 2) Parking and Garaging of Road Vehicles, January 1, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      Permanent International Association of Road Congresses
    - The Use of Accident Records, January 1, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      Burton W. Marsh
    - Traffic Surveys. Practical Methods for Planners and Road Engineers., January 1, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      R.B. Hounsfield
    - Tables from "The Daily Movement of Population Into Central Business Districts", ca. 1948 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      Donald Foley, Dept. of Sociology, Univ. of Rochester
    - Traffic Surveys By Post Cards, January 1, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      Highway Research Board
    - Road Toll. Must This Go On?, October 1, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Traffic Speed and Volume Measurements, January 1, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      Highway Research Board, National Academy of Sciences,
  - Highways- Traffic- General (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Organizing Your Community for Traffic Safety, February 17, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Right-of-way Problems, January 1, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Channelization of Motor Traffic, January 1, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      W.L. Waters, et al, American Society of Civil Engineers
    - A Policy of Sight Distance For Highways, January 1, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Traffic Improvement Program, February 8, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      Governor's Commission on Metropolitan Transportation (Rhode Island)
    - The Road Way to Safety, July 1, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      British Road Federation
    - A Proposed Method For Origin and Destination Surveys, February 1, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      Ozdemir A. Atman
    - The First Thirty-Five Years of Motor Vehicle Experience, January 1, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      Sidney D. Waldon, Detroit
    - Steady Rise in Highway Accidents Reported At New York Conference, April 20, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      Engineering News-Record
    - The Motorist Speaks Summary, July 1, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 28)